One of the quickest ways to learn how to jump rope, I'll have a lot of new people come in and they'll say I haven't jumped rope since I was a kid or I've never jumped rope, and I'll see them over in the corner struggling with their jump roping.
And other people come in and they already know how to jump rope and they're doing great and you know, people are watching each other.
But with the people that are having trouble, I tell them come on over here and bring your jump rope and then I say OK, let me show you how to jump rope.
So they hand me their jump rope and I take the jump rope and I say the best way, and they think they're going to see me jump rope, wrong.
What I do is, I take the jump rope and I say the first thing you do is you take your jump rope and you set it aside, OK?
Just get rid of the jump rope completely for a minute.
Now what you're going to do is you're going to get in a position for jump roping and you're going to make believe you have a jump rope, OK?
So we're going to start hopping on the two feet and we're going to make our hands go down in that slow circle.
As your hands go down, your feet come up, OK?
And just make believe you've got a jump rope, OK?
And then at some point you can do the twice on one foot, twice on the other, and breath.
But make sure your hands are not going into big circles, OK?.
Make sure your feet are not going way up and a good place to do this is actually in the mirror.
Once you do that for a two minute round, in fact I've even had some of the kids doing them for three two minute rounds, because you'll actually get the same workout without the jump rope anyway, but you look kind of foolish sometimes when the other boxers are looking at you and you don't have a jump rope and you're still jumping.
But the best way to learn how to jump rope, take the jump rope, set it aside, go through the motions.
You can do it right in the mirror so you can see yourself.
Up and down, try it, I'll bet you'll be surprised.